let questions =
[
    {"Question":"How many Kit-Kats would it take to span the diameter the universe ?", "Answer":"28"},
    {"Question":"How many Earths could fit in the Sun? ", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many Google Employees are there? ", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"What is the combined net worth of the top 10% of Americans?", "Answer":"14"},
    {"Question":"How many Coca-Cola drinks are consumed each day?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How heavy is the Eiffel Tower in feathers?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many baseballs are used in the MLB each regular season? ", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many whiskers are there on household cats in the United States? ", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How large were Amazon’s 2017 fulfillment expenses in dollars?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many softballs would it take to equal the mass of Earth? ", "Answer":"25"},
    {"Question":"How many inches could you walk for the duration of a year if you keep walking?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"What is the depth, in picometers, of the Mariana Trench?", "Answer":"16"},
    {"Question":"If it were possible, how many pennies would be necessary if placed next to each other, to equal the length of the circumference of Io (the moon of Jupiter)?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"How many times does an average person blink in their lifetime?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How many square inches of iPhone glass in the world? ", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"How many text messages are sent in the US in a year? ", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"How many searches are there on Google each year? ", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"How many ducks are in the US? ", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many server requests are made for 20M internet users each hour?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How many total Reddit accounts are there? ", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many fatal shark attacks have there been from 1958-2016?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many stuffed animals would it take to balance out the weight of a house?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"What is the area of Madagascar, in square angstroms?", "Answer":"32"},
    {"Question":"How tall, in feet, is the 22nd tallest building in the world? ", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"What is 7^43?", "Answer":"36"},
    {"Question":"What is the mass of Mars in iPhone 5s?", "Answer":"25"},
    {"Question":"How many Apps have been downloaded from Apple’s iTunes Store?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many different sets of 5 can you pick from a group of 50?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"In 2004, how many people worldwide died in motor vehicle accidents?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many seconds has it been since Thomas Jefferson was born?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many stories tall is the tallest human ever to live?", "Answer":"0"},
    {"Question":"How many atoms are in your body?", "Answer":"28"},
    {"Question":"How many chicken wing segments were consumed during the 2013 Super Bowl?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How many bytes of digital information does humanity produce each day?", "Answer":"18"},
    {"Question":"What was the estimated size, in bytes, of the library of Congress in 1949?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"If you were to count from one to a quintillion, and took a second to visualize each number (audibly counting would take a lot longer), how long would it take, in years?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many kegs (as in beer) could you fill with the amount of liquid the average person drinks in a year?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"Hurricane Sandy was devastating and expensive. If you had a pile of pennies equal in value to Sandy’s cost, what would be its weight in troy ounces? ", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"What is the distance, in nautical miles, from the dot to the stem on this: i", "Answer":"-16"},
    {"Question":"I traveled to Stone MS from UVA. How far, in megaparsecs, did I travel (assuming I stopped for coffee on the way)?", "Answer":"-19"},
    {"Question":"What is the population of the world’s 70th most populous nation?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"United Airlines is the largest airline in the world. How many planes comprise their fleet?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"What is the average February high temperature in Washington DC, in °D?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"The My Lai Massacre occurred on this date in 1968. According to the US army, how many people were killed?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"What fraction of earth’s water supply is contained within living beings (all forms of life)?", "Answer":"-4"},
    {"Question":"Archimedes famously placed an upper bound on the number of grains of sand needed to fill the entire universe: One vigintillion. How many grains of sand did he suggest? ", "Answer":"63"},
    {"Question":"How many different types of proteins are in the human body?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many different amino acids are?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"How many hairs are on the average human head?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many ml of saliva does a human produce in a lifetime?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many red blood cells are in one human body?", "Answer":"13"},
    {"Question":"How many toothpicks can be made from a cord of wood?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many seconds does it take a dog to locate the direction of a sound?", "Answer":"-3"},
    {"Question":"How many taste buds are on a human tongue?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"The diameter of a DNA molecule in inches.", "Answer":"-4"},
    {"Question":"How many base pairs are in one nucleus of one cell?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many diapers are thrown out in the U.S. each year?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many years is the ½ life of Carbon-14?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"How many years does it take for Styrofoam to biodegrade?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"What is the amount of energy used in kWh for the average search query on Google?", "Answer":"-4"},
    {"Question":"How many gallons of gasoline are burned each day?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How many active volcanoes are on the surface of the earth?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"What is the age of the Earth in seconds?", "Answer":"17"},
    {"Question":"The approximate weight of a 150lb person if they were able to stand on the surface of the sun?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"The number of years ago that Pangaea existed as a supercontinent?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"The speed of the Earth in miles per hour that it travels through space?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"111,111,111^2", "Answer":"16"},
    {"Question":"How many pounds of food are eaten by one human in one lifetime?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"The mass of the earth in tons?", "Answer":"22"},
    {"Question":"How many ways can you make change for a dollar?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many dimples are on a U.S. regulation golf ball?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many times will you blink this year?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"What is the speed of a sneeze in cm/s?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many kilometers long is the Great Barrier Reef?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"The speed of light in m/s.", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"Number of galaxies in the universe.", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"Pounds of skin shed by a person in his or her lifetime.", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"How many seconds would it take a heavy object to sink into the deepest part of the ocean?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"The number of neutrinos that are produced from the sun that pass through your body while you read this sentence.", "Answer":"15"},
    {"Question":"Number of miles the universe expands in one hour.", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"The number of stars in our solar system.", "Answer":"0"},
    {"Question":"Average number of seconds a Koala spends sleeping each day", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"The number of atoms in one mole.", "Answer":"24"},
    {"Question":"How many seconds will it take to fully and quickly write out the number of 1 google if you were not allowed to use scientific notation?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"How many feet above sea level is the highest point of Florida?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many square miles are the 48 contiguous U.S. states?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many people in the U.S. are unemployed?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"What is the population density (people per square mile) in the country of Mali?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"How many miles are between Stockholm and Paris?", "Answer":""},
    {"Question":"How many toothpicks are required to cover a baseball diamond if the tooth picks are lying flat and sideby-side?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"What is the maximum weight, in tons, of a Giant Sequoia tree?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"How many 7-11 stores are there in Virginia?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"How many babies are born each year in the world?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many stone blocks were used to build the pyramid at Giza?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many milk cows are in the U.S.?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many steps does the average American walk during their lifetime?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"How many dollar bills would need to be stacked to reach the moon?", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"How many tennis balls does it take to cover the playing surface of a tennis court (including the doubles alley)?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"What is the maximum speed of the garden snail in mph?", "Answer":"-2"},
    {"Question":"How many metric tons of fish are caught in the country of Jordan each year?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"How many decimeters deep is the Marianas Trench?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many liters of water are there is an Olympic-sized swimming pool?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many federal, state, and local governmental employees are there in the U.S.?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many popular votes separated Obama and McCain during the 2008 presidential election?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many car miles were avoided in 2010 by buses that took kids to school?", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"What is the volume of the average adult in dekaliters?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"If the annual interest that is owed on the national debt each year were divided equally amongst all U.S. citizens, how much would each citizen owe?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"How many troy ounces of gold were produced last year?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many earths are needed to have the equivalent weight of one Sun? ", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many gas stations are there in the U.S.?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many golf balls will fit in a 747?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many cups of coffee does Starbucks sell each year?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How many watts of solar power are/were produced in the U.S. today at noon?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many stars are in the Milky Way Galaxy?", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"How many kilometers does light travel between two consecutive visits of Haley’s comet? ", "Answer":"15"},
    {"Question":"How many electrons flow through a 3 Amp wire each minute?", "Answer":"21"},
    {"Question":"How many milligrams does the earth weigh?", "Answer":"31"},
    {"Question":"What percent of the world's water is in rivers?", "Answer":"-4"},
    {"Question":"How many farms are there in Virginia?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"How many miles of railroad are operational in the U.S.?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many different species of spiders and scorpions are there in the world?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many cells die naturally (apoptosis) in your body during the time that it takes you to solve the average Fermi problem? ", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many joules does the sun emit per second?", "Answer":"26"},
    {"Question":"What is the frequency of an FM radio signal, in cycles per second?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"What is the wavelength of an FM radio signal, in meters?", "Answer":"0"},
    {"Question":"Forrest Gump ran from the coast of Maine to Los Angeles. How many steps did he take?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many stacked LEGO blocks would it take to reach the height of the Empire state Building?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"I’d like to make an actual-size replica of the Empire state Building. Now how many standard 2x4 LEGO blocks would I need?", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"How long, in hours, does it take for a beam of light to traverse the continental US?", "Answer":"-6"},
    {"Question":"How old is the Earth, in seconds?", "Answer":"17"},
    {"Question":"How many nanometers span the entire range of visible light?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many nanometers are in a megaparsec?", "Answer":"31"},
    {"Question":"How many milliliters of blood does the American Red Cross collect in the US in a given year?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many atoms of lead would make a ton of lead?", "Answer":"27"},
    {"Question":"How many paperclips would I need to make a chain long enough to reach the moon from the Earth?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many drops of water are in a full bathtub?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many bones are in the human body?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"What is the Dow Jones Industrial Average?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"How many miles of highway make up the US Interstate Highway system?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"Estimate the mass in grams of all the fans at a home Phillies game.", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"How many days would it take you to count to a million?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"How many electrons pass through a 100 watt light bulb in a minute?", "Answer":"22"},
    {"Question":"How many dollars would a quadrillionaire have?", "Answer":"15"},
    {"Question":"How many leaves are on a mature, healthy oak tree?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"What is the area (in cm2 ) of the leaves on a mature, healthy oak tree?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"I bought a 2 terabyte hard drive. How many bytes of information can it hold?", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"How many light-years is the distance from the Earth to the Sun? ", "Answer":"-5"},
    {"Question":"Two people stand on opposite sides of the Earth. What is the gravitational force between them?", "Answer":"-21"},
    {"Question":"How many 500 milliliter bottles of water laid end to end would it take to stretch across the state of Pennsylvania at its widest point?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How much water in gallons will be used by the populace of Pennsylvania in a year?", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"According to the 2010 census what is the US population under the age of 18?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"According to the 2010 census what is the expected total annual income for the state of Pennsylvania’s population?", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"2^47", "Answer":"14"},
    {"Question":"How many smart phones are owned by the US Population?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"In light years, how tall is the tallest building in the world?", "Answer":"-13"},
    {"Question":"How far, in centimeters, will light travel in one fortnight?", "Answer":"16"},
    {"Question":"In millimeters, what is the distance across the Milky Way Galaxy?", "Answer":"24"},
    {"Question":"23!*37!*41!", "Answer":"115"},
    {"Question":"How many hectares (hec) are there in the United States?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"What is the circumference of the earth in petameters?", "Answer":"-8"},
    {"Question":"What is the circumference of the Earth’s orbit in kilometers?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"If every person living in New York State donated a nickel to charity, how many dollars would have been donated?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"How many hours would it take Americans to consume enough bottled water to circle the entire equator with plastic bottles laid end to end?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"How many jelly beans would it take to fill a regulation NBA basketball?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"What is the surface area of Mars in square meters?", "Answer":"14"},
    {"Question":"What fraction of one year is equal to one second?", "Answer":"-8"},
    {"Question":"What is the number of electrons in a liter of water?", "Answer":"26"},
    {"Question":"How many servings of Coca-Cola are served every year worldwide?", "Answer":"12"},
    {"Question":"How many yoctoseconds did it take the 2011 New York Marathon top men’s finisher to complete the race?", "Answer":"28"},
    {"Question":"What is the dollar total of the money that comes in a standard Monopoly game?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"The odds in winning the Mega Millions lottery in the US are one in how many?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"How many quills does the typical porcupine have?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"How many males residing in the US are fully or partially color blind?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How many dogs are owned in the United States?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"How many seconds of television does the average American watch in a year?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"In cubic meters, what is the volume of the Sun?", "Answer":"27"},
    {"Question":"How many cases of food-borne botulism occur in the United States annually?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"What is the lethal dose of botulism toxin, in grams, for a 150 pound human?", "Answer":"-7"},
    {"Question":"According to the Census of Marine Life, what is the estimated number of species in the world’s oceans?", "Answer":"5"},
    {"Question":"How many different species of fish did the Census of Marine Life discover in the past year?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many Christmas trees were produced in Ohio last year?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"At what distance from Earth’s surface, in meters, can an astronaut observe the entire hemisphere directly beneath them?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"How much voltage can a large electric eel produce?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"Up to how many MeV may the energy of gamma rays extend during the course of nuclear reactions initiated by low energy particles?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"What is the distance, in meters, of a satellite in geosynchronous orbit about the Earth?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"What is the distance from the Sun to Pluto measured in meters?", "Answer":"13"},
    {"Question":"According to the U.S. Bureau of the Census, what was the resident population of the United States on 1/1/2005?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"What is the average diameter of a human hair in millimeters?", "Answer":"-1"},
    {"Question":"How many square kilometers of Lake Erie are solely under the jurisdiction of the USA?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"How many pounds of landfill waste would be generated by the population of Cuyahoga county in one year?", "Answer":"9"},
    {"Question":"What is the annual consumption of ice cream, in pounds, for the State of Ohio?", "Answer":"8"},
    {"Question":"What is the ratio of meters of the highest and lowest point in Colorado compared to the highest and lowest point in Minnesota?", "Answer":"1"},
    {"Question":"What is the average rate of continental drift, in meters per day, along the MidAtlantic Ridge?", "Answer":"-4"},
    {"Question":"How many total kg of carbon monoxide were produced in 2001 in the US as Air Pollutant Emissions?", "Answer":"11"},
    {"Question":"What fraction of a cubic meter is a milliliter?", "Answer":"-6"},
    {"Question":"What is the length, in meters, of the shortest form of an X-ray wavelength?", "Answer":"-11"},
    {"Question":"How many seconds were cell phones used in 2003 by the U.S. population?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"How many organic and inorganic substances were registered with the Chemical Abstracts service as of Jan.1, 2005?", "Answer":"7"},
    {"Question":"What is the number of somatic cells in a 49 day old, normally developing fetus?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many genes are currently considered part of the human genome?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"If the earth became 10X denser than it was originally, what would the radius of earth have to be (meters) to have the same gravitational attraction?", "Answer":"6"},
    {"Question":"If an object with the mass of the sun had the radius of planck's length what is its escape velocity?", "Answer":"27"},
    {"Question":"How many photons of light does the sun emit in a second?", "Answer":"45"},
    {"Question":"If a 220 lb man runs at the speed of light, how many Calories of energy will be used?", "Answer":"15"},
    {"Question":"A sphere has the radius of 1 meter. How many Earths do you have to cram into the object to create a black hole?", "Answer":"2"},
    {"Question":"How many trees are in the United States?", "Answer":"10"},
    {"Question":"If all the water in the Great Lakes were turned into a cumulus cloud, what volume (in milliliters) would it occupy?", "Answer":"26"},
    {"Question":"If the earth was actually a hollow sphere with no mantle or core, only crust, what would its mass be, in kilograms?", "Answer":"22"},
    {"Question":"How many gallons of 100°C water could a barrel of oil vaporize?", "Answer":"3"},
    {"Question":"How many moles of gas comprise Jupiter?", "Answer":"30"},
    {"Question":"A ship over the deepest point in the Great Lakes sends an acoustic pulse downwards to measure the depth. How many seconds does it take for the signal to return?", "Answer":"0"},
    {"Question":"How many newtons would an adult elephant weigh on Mars?", "Answer":"4"},
    {"Question":"What is the momentum, in kg·m/s, of a golf ball-sized hailstone?", "Answer":"0"},
    {"Question":"How many raindrops fall globally each day?", "Answer":"20"},
    {"Question":"What is the energy equivalent of the mass of the average human, in joules?", "Answer":"19"},
    {"Question":"How many tonnes of dissolved salts are in the world’s oceans?", "Answer":"16"}
]
var x = Math.floor(30 * Math.random()+1);
var y = Math.floor(30 * Math.random()+1);
initialPoints = 0;
var specific = questions[Math.floor(questions.length*Math.random())];

let maths =     
[
    {"Question":"" + x + " ^ " + y + "", "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(Math.pow(x,y))) + ""}
]
let beat = new Audio('/Users/dewaynebarnes/Downloads/ding.mp3');
let small =
[
        // use kilograms and cubic meters pls
    {
        "name": "Iphone",
        "mass": "0.112",
        "volume": "0.000055135568",
    },
    {
        "name": "feather",
        "mass": "1.9",
        "volume": 2* 10**-6,
    },
    {
        "name": "brick",
        "mass": "3.4",
        "volume": 0.000768,
    },    
    {
        "name": "pencil",
        "mass": "0.008",
        "volume": 7 * 10**-6,
    },
]
let large =
[
    // use kilograms and cubic meters pls
    {
        "name": "Sun",
        "mass": 1.989 * 10**30,
        "volume": 1.4 * 10**27,
    },
    {
        "name": "Moon",
        "mass": 7.34767309  * 10**22,
        "volume": 2.19 * 10**19,
    },
    {
        "name": "Eiffel Tower",
        "mass": 7341214,
        "volume": 930,
    },
    {
        "name": "Mount Everest",
        "mass": 810 * 10**9,
        "volume": 1400000000000,
    },
]
let spheres =
[
    // use kilograms and cubic meters pls and meters
    {
        "name": "Tennis Ball",
        "mass": 0.0577,
        "volume": 0.000131097,
        "circumfrence": 0.21,
    },
    {
        "name": "golf ball",
        "mass": "0.04569",
        "volume": 40.6843720 * 10 ** -6,
        "circumfrence": 0.134112,
    },
    {
        "name": "basketball",
        "mass": "0.5863",
        "volume": 0.011100338639,
        "circumfrence": 0.75,
    },

]
let distances =
[
    // use kilometers
    {
        "name": "Continential United States",
        "length": 5000,
    },
    {
        "name": "Football Feild",
        "length": 0.09144,
    },

]
let sounds =
[
    // use decibels
    {
        "name": "ticking watch",
        "decibels": 20,
    },
    {
        "name": "whisper",
        "decibels": 30,
    },
    {
        "name": "average room noise",
        "decibels": 40,
    },
    {
        "name": "rainfall",
        "decibels": 50,
    },
    {
        "name": "background music",
        "decibels": 60,
    },
    {
        "name": "normal conversation",
        "decibels": 60,
    },
    {
        "name": "average office noise",
        "decibels": 70,
    },
    {
        "name": "thunder",
        "decibels": 120,
    },
]
let bodies =
[
    // use m/s^2 cubic m and kg
    {
        "name": "Mercury",
        "mass": 3.285 * 10**23 ,
        "volume": 6.08 * 10**19,
        "gravity": 3.7,
    },
    {
        "name": "Venus",
        "mass": 4.867 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 9.2843 * 10**20,
        "gravity": 3.7,
    },
    {
        "name": "Earth",
        "mass": 5.97 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 1.08321 * 10**21,
        "gravity": 9.8,
    },
    {
        "name": "Mars",
        "mass": 0.642 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 1.6318 * 10**20,
        "gravity": 1.6,
    },
    {
        "name": "Jupiter",
        "mass": 1898 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 1.43128 * 10**24,
        "gravity": 23.1,
    },
    {
        "name": "Saturn",
        "mass": 568 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 8.2713 * 10**23,
        "gravity": 9.0,
    },
    {
        "name": "Uranus",
        "mass": 86.8 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 6.833 * 10**22,
        "gravity": 8.7,
    },
    {
        "name": "Neptune",
        "mass": 102 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 6.254 * 10**22,
        "gravity": 11.0,
    },
    {
        "name": "Pluto",
        "mass": 0.0130 * 10**24 ,
        "volume": 7.15 * 10**18,
        "gravity": 0.7,
    },
]
small = small.concat(spheres);
large = large.concat(bodies);
s = Math.floor(small.length * Math.random());
l = Math.floor(large.length * Math.random());
let custom = 
[ 
    {"Question":"How many " + small[s].name+ "s "+" can fit in the "+large[l].name, "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(large[l].volume/small[s].volume))}
]
function setCustom(){
    s = Math.floor(small.length * Math.random());
    s2 = Math.floor(small.length * Math.random());
    l = Math.floor(large.length * Math.random());
    sp = Math.floor(spheres.length * Math.random());
    d = Math.floor(distances.length * Math.random());
    so = Math.floor(sounds.length * Math.random());
    so2 = Math.floor(sounds.length * Math.random());
    first = Math.floor(50 * Math.random())/10.0;
    b = Math.floor(bodies.length * Math.random());
    b2 = Math.floor(bodies.length * Math.random());
    second = Math.floor(50 * Math.random() + 50)/10.0;
    custom =
    [
        {"Question":"How many " + small[s].name+ "s "+"can fit in the "+large[l].name +" ?", "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(large[l].volume/small[s].volume))},
        {"Question":"How many " + small[s].name+ "s "+"would it take to fill the "+large[l].name +" ?", "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(large[l].volume/small[s].volume))},
        {"Question":"What is the weight of the " + large[l].name + " in " +small[s].name +"s ?", "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(large[l].mass/small[s].mass))},
        {"Question":"What is the equivelant amount of energy in joules of a " + small[s].name , "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(small[s].mass*((3*10**8)**2)))},
        {"Question":"What is the equivelant amount of energy in joules of the " + large[l].name , "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(large[l].mass*((3*10**8)**2)))},
        {"Question":"If a " + spheres[sp].name + " rolled across " +distances[d].name +" how many revolutions would it make?", "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10((1000*distances[d].length)/spheres[sp].circumfrence))},
        {"Question":"How much louder is " + sounds[so].name + " than a " + sounds[so2].name +" ?", "Answer": Math.round((sounds[so].decibels-sounds[so2].decibels)/10)},
        {"Question":"How much more enrgy is released by a " + second + " magnitude earthquake than a " + first + " ?", "Answer": Math.round(Math.log10((31**(second -first))))},
        {"Question":"What would the ratio of weight be between a " + small[s].name + " on " + bodies[b].name + " and a "+ small[s2].name + " on the "+ bodies[b2].name, "Answer": Math.round(Math.log10(small[s].mass*bodies[b].gravity/(small[s2].mass*bodies[b2].gravity)))},
    ]
}
function setMath(){
    x = Math.floor(100*Math.random()+1);
    y = Math.floor(100*Math.random()+1);
    maths =
    [
        {"Question":x + " ^ " + y, "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(x**y))},
        {"Question":x + "!", "Answer": Math.floor(Math.log10(factorialize(x)))}
    ]
}

function factorialize(n){
    if(n > 1){
        return n * factorialize(n-1);
    } else {
        return 1;
    }
}
var streak = 0;
var points = 0;
slider = document.getElementById("myRange");

function randomize(){
    if(Math.random() > .9){
        specific = questions[Math.floor(questions.length*Math.random())];
    } else if (Math.random() > .1) {
        setCustom();
        specific = custom[Math.floor(custom.length*Math.random())];
    } else {
        setMath();
        specific = maths[Math.floor(maths.length*Math.random())];
    }
}

function setQuestion(){
    document.getElementById("Question").textContent = specific.Question;
}
function setStreak(){
    document.getElementById("Streak").textContent = "Streak: "+streak;
}
function setPoints(){
    document.getElementById("Points").textContent = "Points: "+points;
    document.getElementById("PointChange").textContent = points-initialPoints;
    document.getElementById("PointChange").style.visibility = "visible";
    if(points-initialPoints >= 0){
        document.getElementById('PointChange').style.animation = 'slideout 1s';
    }else{
        document.getElementById('PointChange').style.animation = 'slidein 1s';
    }
    setTimeout(setNone, 1000);
}
function setPrev(){
    document.getElementById("PrevAnswer").textContent = "PrevAns: "+specific.Answer;
}
function setNone(){
    document.getElementById("PointChange").style.visibility = "hidden";
    document.getElementById('PointChange').style.animation = 'none';
}
function check(){
    if(specific.Answer == document.getElementById("type").value){
        document.getElementById("Question").style.boxShadow = ' 0 0 30px #00ff00';
        streak++;
    } else {
        document.getElementById("Question").style.boxShadow = "  0 0 30px #ff0000";
        streak = 0;
    }
    addPoints();
}
function addPoints() {
    var guess = document.getElementById("type").value
    var multiplier = 0.02 * slider.value;
    initialPoints = points;
    specific.Answer = parseInt(specific.Answer);
    if ((guess >= specific.Answer && guess >= 0 && specific.Answer >= 0)) {
        if (guess * (1 - (1 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 100 * ((streak / 2) + 1);
            beat.play();
            document.getElementById("Question").style.boxShadow = ' 0 0 30px #00ff00';
        } else if (guess * (1 - (2 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 90;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (3 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 80;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (4 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 70;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (5 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 60;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (6 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 50;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (7 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 40;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (8 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 30;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (9 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 20;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (10 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 10;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (11 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 0;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (12 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 10;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (13 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 20;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (14 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 30;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (15 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 40;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (16 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 50;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (17 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 60;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (18 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 70;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (19 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 80;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (20 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 90;
        } else {
            points -= 100;
        }
    } else if (guess <= specific.Answer && guess <= 0 && specific.Answer <= 0) {
        if (guess * (1 - (1 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 100 * ((streak / 2) + 1);
            beat.play();
            document.getElementById("Question").style.boxShadow = ' 0 0 30px #00ff00';
        } else if (guess * (1 - (2 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 90;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (3 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 80;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (4 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 70;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (5 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 60;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (6 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 50;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (7 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 40;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (8 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 30;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (9 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 20;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (10 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 10;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (11 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 0;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (12 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 10;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (13 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 20;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (14 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 30;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (15 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 40;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (16 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 50;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (17 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 60;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (18 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 70;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (19 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 80;
        } else if (guess * (1 - (20 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 90;
        } else {
            points -= 100;
        }
    } else if (guess >= specific.Answer && guess <= 0 && specific.Answer <= 0) {
        if (guess * (1 + (1 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 100 * ((streak / 2) + 1);
            beat.play();
            document.getElementById("Question").style.boxShadow = ' 0 0 30px #00ff00';
        } else if (guess * (1 + (2 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 90;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (3 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 80;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (4 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 70;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (5 * multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 60;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (6 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 50;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (7 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 40;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (8 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 30;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (9 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 20;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (10 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 10;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (11 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points += 0;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (12 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 10;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (13 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 20;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (14 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 30;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (15 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 40;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (16 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 50;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (17 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 60;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (18 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 70;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (19 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 80;
        } else if (guess * (1 + (20 * multiplier)) <= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 90;
        } else {
            points -= 100;
        }
    } else if ((guess > 0 && specific.Answer < 0) || (guess < 0 && specific.Answer > 0)) {
        points -= 100;
    } else {
        if(guess * (1+(1*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 100*((streak/2)+1);
            beat.play();
            document.getElementById("Question").style.boxShadow = ' 0 0 30px #90EE90';
        } else if(guess * (1+(2*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 90;
        } else if(guess * (1+(3*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 80;
        } else if(guess * (1+(4*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 70;
        } else if(guess * (1+(5*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 60;
        } else if(guess * (1+(6*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 50;
        } else if(guess * (1+(7*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 40;
        } else if(guess * (1+(8*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 30;
        } else if(guess * (1+(9*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer){
            points += 20;
        } else if(guess * (1+(10*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 10;
        } else if(guess * (1+(11*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points += 0;
        } else if(guess * (1+(12*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 10;
        } else if(guess * (1+(13*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 20;
        } else if(guess * (1+(14*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 30;
        } else if(guess * (1+(15*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 40;
        } else if(guess * (1+(16*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 50;
        } else if(guess * (1+(17*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 60;
        } else if(guess * (1+(18*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 70;
        } else if(guess * (1+(19*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 80;
        } else if(guess * (1+(20*multiplier)) >= specific.Answer) {
            points -= 90;
        } else {
            points -= 100;
        }
    }
    if(points > 0){
        document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--points',  '#90EE90');
    }else{
        document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--points',  '#FF7276');
    }
    if(points-initialPoints >= 0){
        document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--points2',  '#90EE90');
    }else{
        document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--points2',  '#FF7276');
    }
}
slider.oninput = function() {
    var newcolor = (slider.value -1) * 30;
    document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--main-bg-color', newcolor);
}
window.addEventListener("mousemove", e => {
    let xPos = e.clientX;
    let yPos = e.clientY;
    let height = window.innerHeight;
    document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--hue', xPos/2 + "deg");
    document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--light', (yPos/height * 100) + "%");

})

